Worlds collide.
Percy Jackson & the Olympians: The Lightning Thief is a adventure,
fantasy, family film directed by Chris Columbus.
Accident prone teenager, Percy discovers he's actually a demi-God, the son of
Poseidon, and he is needed when Zeus' lightning is stolen.
Percy must master his new found skills in order to prevent a war
between the Gods that could devastate the entire world.
Percy Jackson, played by Logan Lerman.
Grover Underwood, played by Brandon T. Jackson.
Annabeth Chase, played by Alexandra Daddario.
Luke Castellan, played by Jake Abel.
Mr. Brunner / Chiron, played by Pierce Brosnan.
Zeus, played by Sean Bean.
Percy Jackson & the Olympians is a fantasy novel
series by American author Rick Riordan.
It is the first of four book series in the Camp Half-Blood Chronicles, preceding The
Heroes of Olympus, The Trials of Apollo, and The Nico di Angelo Adventures.
The novels are set in a world with the Greek gods in the 21st century.
The series follows the protagonist, Percy Jackson, a young demigod who must
prevent the Titans, led by Kronos, from destroying the world.
The first three books were published in the United States by Miramax Books before they
were folded into Hyperion Books; that house published the remaining books.
All the books were published in the United Kingdom by Penguin Books.
Four supplementary books, along with graphic novel versions of
the first five books, have also been released.
By January 2022, the books had sold more than 180 million copies
worldwide, making the series one of the best-selling of all time.
A follow-up trilogy in the series, The Senior Year Adventures, takes place after the events
of The Heroes of Olympus and began in 2023 with The Chalice of the Gods.
Three sequel series, The Heroes of Olympus, The Trials of
Apollo, and The Nico di Angelo Adventures, follow.
The first book was adapted as a film titled Percy Jackson &
the Olympians: The Lightning Thief (2010).
It was commercially successful but received mixed reviews from
critics and the audience for its departure from the book.
The first book was also adapted into a musical.
The second book was adapted as a film titled Percy Jackson: Sea of
Monsters (2013), which also received mixed reviews.
A TV series based on the novels premiered on
Disney+ in 2023 to positive reviews.
The film explores themes of monster, based on novel or
book, greek mythology, dyslexia, god.